Mohamed Kemoh Rogers | Dr

Mobile: +232 (79) 584026 +44 (79) 56211798

Email: kemorogers@njala.edu.sl

kemorogers@yahoo.co.uk

ACADEMIC INFO

Kemoh qualified as registered nurse, adults in 1997 and gained in-patient and out-patient experiences in acute medical nursing and STIs/HIV/AIDS before taking up lecturer positions. He received his PhD in Public Health at City, University of London, where he was guest lecturer, which he did alongside clinical practice.

He then took up a fulltime position as senior lecturer in Adult Nursing and Public Health with Anglia Ruskin University in 2010. He had recurrent positions of course leader and admissions tutor for BSc Public Health. He taught and lead modules on the MSc Public Health programmes and supervised several PhD theses. Also taught cohorts of international nurses including those on adaptation programmes.

Kemoh was Associate Professor in Nursing Sciences with University of East Anglia, Norwich and organised, lead, and taught a series of nursing modules at undergraduate and postgraduate levels (please see below for details). He also supervised several ProfDoc students.

He is currently Associate Professor and Head of Department, Public Health with Njala University, Department of Environmental Health Sciences, School of Health Sciences where he is involved with teaching and leading courses on the BSc Nursing, BSc Public Health, MSC Public Health programs and PhD teaching and supervision.

His main research interests have included concordance to medications and the experiences of couples and individuals living with discordant chronic infections (STI/HIV) (where only one partner is infected), using grounded theory methodology and Interpretive Phenomenology informed by pragmatism and symbolic interactionism as theoretical frameworks.

Career summary

Employer	Job Title	Period of Employment
Njala University	Associate Professor,	March 2022 -
University of Makeni, Sierra Leone	Research Professor in Public Health	January 2021- March 2022
University of East Anglia	Associate Professor, Nursing Sciences	February 2020- January 2021
University of East Anglia	Senior Lecturer, Nursing Sciences	2017-2020
Anglia Ruskin University	Senior Lecturer, Nursing and Public Health	2010-2017
Homerton University Hospital, London	Clinical Nurse Specialist HIV/AIDS	2004-2010

University Hospital Lewisham, London	Clinical Nurse Specialist HIV/AIDS	2002-2004
Newham General Hospital (NHS) Trust, London	Staff Nurse HIV/AIDS	2001-2002
Newham General Hospital (NHS) Trust	Link Nurse HIV/AIDS	1999-2001
Newham General Hospital (NHS) Trust	Staff Nurse	1997-1999
YAMS Agricultural Enterprises, Gambia,	Field Agronomist and Farm Manager	1991-1993
Agrotech Agricultural Ltd, The Gambia	Field Agronomist	1990-1991
St. Joseph's Blama, Sierra Leone	Assistant Teacher, Physics, Biology, Chemistry	1988-1990

Teaching activity and expertise

Main current academic management responsibilities		
Role	Pathway/course/module	
Associate Professor	MSc and PhD Public Health	
Senior Lecturer/Associate Professor	Nursing Sciences	
Module organiser/Teacher	Managing Care	
Module organiser/Teacher	Psychosocial Perspectives of Care Delivery TNA	
Module organiser/Teacher	Essential nursing practice BSc (Hons) Nursing	
Module organiser/Teacher	Essential nursing practice Nursing Degree Apprenticeship	
Module organiser/Teacher	Pharmacology for Nurses TNA	
Module organiser/Teacher	Diagnostic interpretation MSc	
Module organiser/Teacher	BSc, MSc, PhD/ProfDoc	

Previous academic teaching/management responsibilities			
Role	Pathway/course/module		
Senior Lecturer	Public Health (BSc/MSc), PhD supervision		
Module leader	Health Promotion for Health and Social Care		
Module leader	Principles in Public Health		

Module leader	Introduction to Economic Evaluation in Public Health (BSc & MSc PH)
Module leader	Introduction to Epidemiology
Module leader	Addictions & Communicable Disease Management (MSc PH)
Module leader	Fundamentals of Anatomy and Physiology
Module leader	Systematic and Scoping Review Methodology (MSc PH)
Module leader	Introduction to research methods
Course leader	BSc Public Health
Major Project supervision	BSc Public Health
Major Project supervision	MSc Public Health
Research supervision	BSc, MSc/PhD
Visiting Lecturer City University of London	CPD NM3118. Advanced STI and HIV/AIDS

Research Degree Supervision				
First/Second/third supervisor	Completions	Chair of PhD Examinations	Examiner	
Five	One	One	2015-2017	
Two			2018-	

Administrative experiences

Course and module developments Students Personal Assistant

Professional Education

Full Title of Qualification	Professional Body	Year Attaine d
Registered Nurse Adult	NMC	1997
ENB934; Management of HIV/AIDS and sexual health	NMC	2000
ENB 280; Advanced management of HIV/AIDS	NMC	2001

Independent Non-medical prescribing	NMC	2009

Qualifications

Full title of Award	Awarding Body	Period of Study	Degree Class	Date of award
PhD Public Health	City University London	2010- 2016	Pass	November 2016
PG Cert (Higher Education)	Anglia Ruskin University, Chelmsford	2010- 2011	Pass	July 2011
MSc Nursing	City University London	2006- 2008	Pass	March 2009
MSc Economic Evaluation	City University London	2001- 2003	pass	Dec 2003
BSc (Hons) Nursing	City University London	1998- 2001	2.2 (upper)	Dec 2001
Diploma Nursing Studies	University of Surrey	1994- 1997	Merit	Dec 1997
School attendance GCSE O'Level	Government Secondary School, Bo and St. Michael's Secondary School, Moyamba	1977- 1983	Division 1	1983

Selected Publications, funding and research activity

- 1. Time of HIV infection and disclosure to current sexual partners: A typology of Serodiscordant Relationships (SdRs) among heterosexual Black African Migrant couples in the United Kingdom (UK). Publishers, Mediscript Ltd, published in HIV Nursing journal volume 18; issue 4
- 2. Sero-risk neutral and sero-risk averse relationships: Perceptions of risk and condom use among Black African heterosexual migrants in Serodiscordant Relationships (SdRs) in the UK. International Journal of STD and AIDS, 0956-4624; 82-87.

In draft:

- 1. Blemished by association: managing courtesy stigma within heterosexual serodiscordant relationships.
- 2. Exploring Interpretive Phenomenological research perspective as Gestalt

Funding: Grants, scholarships and funds

2009	Florence Nightingale Foundation	Research grants	£1,700.00
2010	Homerton University Hospital (NHS) Trust	Nursing PhD Student grant	£ 17,500
2010	NHIVNA/Borrhinger Ingiem	Research Scholarship	£4,450.00

2011	Anglia Ruskin University	Faculty Support Fund Application	£1,929.00
Unsuccess	ful Research Bids		
Year	Funder	Title of Research Bid	Amount
2008	National Institute for Health Research	Research grant	£36,000.00
2010	City University Research Fund	Research grant	£240,000:00
As Academic Consultant	NORWEGIAN CHURCH AID	IDPs in North East Nigeria' perspectives on COVID-19 preventon and control behaviours.	£52,899

Professional affiliations and memberships

Executive Committee Member; National HIV Nurses Association (NHIVNA)

Trustee (Previously deputy Chair) Organisation of Sierra Leonean Health care Professionals Abroad (TOSHPA)

External Activities

External Examiner: MSc Public Health and Health Promotion and Continuing Professional Development

Provision. Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen, Scotland

External Examiner: Anglia Ruskin University, Cambridge, Chelmsford and Peterborough, UK

Chair: Research Sub-Committee, National HIV Nurses Association

Freelance PhD Supervisor: The PhD Bureau, London

Publications, Conferences and seminars

Date Outline of attendance – presentations/abstracts, conference name, location

Conference paper presentations (Selected)

- 1. 30th World Nursing Care Congress, virtual, Keynote presentation. November 29-30, 2021
- 2. NHIVNA Research Initiative for nurses. NHIVNA Annual Conference (virtual) 16-17/06/2021

- 3. Experiencing stigma by association among Black African heterosexual couples in serodiscordant relationships in the UK. 2nd International Conference on Nursing and Healthcare. $19/05/21 \rightarrow 22/05/21$, Paris
- 4. 28th International Conference on Nursing Care Vienna, Austria, May 23-24, 2019. Title: Constructing identities to evade stigma in relationships with one partner living with HIV
- 6th International Conference on Nurse Practitioners, Paris, France, Keynote presentation: June 21-22, 2018, Positioning HIV and communications: Narratives of Black African heterosexual couples in relationships with one HIV positive partner in the UK
- 16th European Doctoral Conference in Nursing Science, Bern, Switzerland, 15-17 September 2016. Constructing identities through selective disclosures of HIV to outsiders: The Lived Experiences of Black African Couples in Serodiscordant Relationships in the UK
- 7. 14th European Doctoral Conference in Nursing Science Maastricht, Netherlands 12-13 September 2014; Constructing Serodiscordant Relationships (SdRs): The Narrative of Couples in Relationships with one HIV Positive Partner (SdRs)
- 8. 13th European Doctoral Conference in Nursing Science Graz, Austria, 14-15 September 2012 Using Constructivist Grounded Theory as Gestalt to Improve Understanding of the Experiences of People living in Relationships where one partner is HIV Positive (HIV Serodiscordant Relationships (HIV SDRs
- 9. National HIV Nurses Association, Liverpool 13-15 June 2012 Manchester, Promoting user involvement (UI) through a holistic nursing framework for the care and management of people with HIV/AIDS as a chronic condition.
- 10. National HIV Nurses Association, Birmingham June 2009; Understanding the perspectives of patients on user involvement group (UIG): the implications for holistic nursing care and management of people with HIV/AIDS as a chronic condition.
- 11. National HIV Nurses Association Glasgow June 2008; HIV-2: Nursing care and management.

Poster Presentations

- (upcoming) 28th International Conference on Nursing Care Vienna, Austria, May 23-24, 2019. Title: Constructing identities to evade stigma in relationships with one partner living with HIV
- 19th Annual Conference of the National HIV Nurses Association (NHIVNA) 22-23 June 2017, Constructing identities through selective disclosures of HIV to outsiders: the lived experiences of black african couples in Serodiscordant Relationships (SdRs) in the UK
- 3. Annual Research Forum, Newham General Hospital 15/11/2011; Qualitative research with COUPLES where one partner is HIV POSITIVE